Adebayo Akingbade

I am your favourite product engineer with years of experience building software applications from the ground up-gathering information, planning, designing, developing, testing, delivering, and maintaining. I'm extremely passionate towards software architectures and designs combined with sensitivity to serve the needs of an organisation.

No. 7 Asajon way, Eti-Osa, Sangotedo, Ajah, Lagos State, Nigeria, NG

(+234) 9018380825 (+234) 8116905441

adejeremih@gmail.com https://github.com/AdebayoAkingbade

EXPERIENCE

eProcess (Ecobank Transnational Incorporated)

January 2023 - Present

- A member of a team that's currently developing a fintech web app designed to manage your finances globally, with a seamless user interface and powerful features using **Angular technology**. Rapid transfer solves the high fees and delays involved in global transactions as it ensures swift and secure cross-border transactions.
- A member of a team that developed a User Access Management (UAM) app used by over 10,000 staff for managing other financial applications across the group using **Angular technology**
- A member of a team that developed an application that helps to automate the declarations made by staff and directors on conflict of interest/commitments and gifts and entertainment declarations made by staff. This was built using

CONCLASE - React Developer and tutor

January 2022 - September 2023

Conclase is a tech company that empowers companies to achieve more through; tech recruiting, web and software development, project outsourcing and capacity building.

SILICON JUNGLE LABS, Austin Texas — Frontend Engineer

May 2021 - June 2022

A member of a team that developed a social money pooling app.

- Built project with GraphQL, React and Typescript.
- Experience in writing unit and integration test

DECAGON, Lagos — Software Engineer

April 2020 - May 2021

A member of a team that developed a social media app.

- Built project with NodeJS, RestAPI, React and Typescript.
- Handles Database Management System with MongoDB
- Experience in writing unit and integration test

TECHNOLOGIES

Nodeis

ExpressJS

GraphQL

MongoDB

Typescript

ReactJS

Microsoft Office

HTML 5

CSS

Postgresql

Firebase

Heroku

Version Control with Git and

Github,

Test-Driven development.

CERTIFICATIONS

DECAGON - Software Engineering

GOOGLE - Foundations of Project Management

VMEdu, Inc at SCRUMstudy-Scrum Fundamentals Certified(SFC)

Freelancer — Web Developer

February 2018 - March 2020

- \bullet Built project with HTML and CSS. \bullet Created websites with great UI/UX designs
- · Helped web developers and companies in debugging

EDUCATION

Kebbi State University of Science and Technology, Aliero — B.Sc

October 2012 - September 2016

Second Class Honor - Bachelor of Science degree in Statistics.

PROJECTS

Cloud Integrated Service App

An application that provides innovative information and communication technology solutions to meet and exceed clients business objectives

Link: https://cloud-int-website.vercel.app/

Luno Landing Page Clone

Iterated user interface and experience to meet user satisfaction and documentation

Standards gotten from market research.

Link: https://luno-page.netlify.app/

Decameal App

A food web application where users can login, explore varieties of food, available in the kitchen and order for their choice.

I contributed to designing and building the dashboard, landing page, and about us page.

Technologies used: ReactJS, Typescript, and RestAPI

Link: https://decameal.netlify.app/

TRUCK LOGISTICS

A web application where customers can order for truck deliveries and registered drivers get paired with orders based on driver location.

Technologies used: NodeJS, ReactJS, Typescript, and Bootsrap

Link: https://trucksnow.netlify.app/

Contact Keeper

A contact saver that helps life even better, you don't have to overdose your phones

With loads anymore. The contact keeper can help to save your contacts and free

up space on your mobile.

Link: https://contact-keep.herokuapp.com/

Tribl — Admin web Application

Tribl is a social money pooling platform building a bridge between Web3 and the culture. Using React, Redux, Docker, GraphQL,